# **Aydin Hassan**

Drakelow Barns, Caldwell Road, Drakelow, Derbyshire, DE159TX **Mobile:** +43 677 63399329 **Email:** aydin@hotmail.co.uk

Web: https://www.aydinhassan.co.uk GitHub: https://github.com/AydinHassan

**Remote Only** 

# **Profile**

I'm a senior PHP developer with extensive experience in building high quality e-commerce and general PHP applications. I work well alone, in a team or as a leader. I have a strong focus on code quality and unit testing and have experience with all the major PHP frameworks including Magento 1/2, ZF2, Symfony, Laravel & Wordpress.

I am interested in working on projects with a team that cares about crafting high quality software, with particular focus on well architected code, unit and integration tests, dependency management and code reviews.

I bring with me experience and a pragmatic, calculated and precise methodology to solve your problems. I learn and adapt fast - which I believe is even more important than tool exposure.

## Qualifications

BSc (First-class honours) Forensic Computing - De Montfort University Sep 2009 - May 2013

1st Year - 75%, 2nd Year - 74.5%, 3rd Year - Placement, 4th Year - 83%

Awards: Faculty of Technology best final year student

**BTEC National Diploma in IT** - Burton College 2004 – 2006

Triple Distinction (Equivalent to 3 A's at A Level)

Magento Developer Plus - 2014

## Work Experience

JH - Senior Magento Developer August 2013 – Present

I worked on a diverse set of projects at various stages, from planning and development to testing and maintenance. I implemented many processes and trained the team including unit testing, code quality, code reviews and continuous integration. I automated many tasks by writing and maintaining a host of tools and applications. I improved versioning processes and migrated 100+ repositories from SVN from GitHub. My proudest moments came from mentoring and teaching other team members through code reviews, pair programming, discussions and meetings. I transitioned the whole team to writing and understanding unit tests. I have been involved with the recruitment process and occasionally ran development team meetings. During my time at JH I also contributed to many open source projects including Magento itself. Client work I've completed can be summarised as data migrations, import/export systems, payment provider integrations, ERP & PIM integrations, API design and construction, Database design and optimisation and much more.

#### Worldwide Clinical Trials, Junior Developer September 2011 – October 2012

I took the position at Worldwide Clinical Trials as part of my university placement year. Throughout the 12-month period I worked on various projects, through different departments. Due to my high performance the

work period was extended. My initial role was as a C developer working on a bespoke database system, fixing bugs and amending existing code. I developed scripts and programs to automate monotonous tasks which were later rolled out to other staff members. I then moved on to a penetration testing exercise for a new product due to be released soon for a major retailer where I found and fixed various high security vulnerabilities. The last period of my employment was focused on developing and maintaining a Zend Framework 1 application and its complex SQL reports, procedures and triggers. I developed a Node.js based notification system fed by database triggers. Towards the end I took over as the lead developer implementing various features to be showcased to customers around the globe.

# **Personal Projects**

PHP School September 2015 - now

https://www.phpschool.io

PHP School is a project created by me and some friends to help others learn to code using an open source learning system for free. We created a framework for teaching programming concepts and verifying the written code. We hope for a community to develop, with many workshops which will provide free programming education for as many topics as there are workshops created - essentially a platform where people can create lesson plans and the system does everything else. There are also enterprise opportunities available which we are investigating for consulting and helping businesses teach people how to use their tools and processes.

#### Wild & without September 2017 - now

https://www.wildandwithout.com

Wild and without is mine and my partner's travel blog. It was built and designed by me using Wordpress and modern frontend tech. We use the blog to write about our travel adventures and to showcase my photography.

## Talks & Workshops

Unconference talk at PHPNW October 2016

https://conference.phpnw.org.uk

I gave a talk with my friend Michael
Woodward about our open source project PHP
School. We won best un-conference talk of the
conference and were invited back to talk at
PHPNW 2017 on the main stage.

## Workshop at PHP Warwickshire August 2017

http://phpwarks.co.uk

I hosted a PHP School workshop with Michael Woodward teaching people how to code PHP with PHP School.

## **Open Source**

I have contributed to a myriad of open source projects and also maintain my own. This is a great chance to inspect my code style & quality - check my GitHub and website for a breakdown. To summarise I have contributed features and fixes to Magento 2, Zend Framework, Composer, PHP Parser, Magerun, Doctrine, Data Import PHP and many more.

**Hobbies -** In my spare time I am travelling the world with my rucksack, tent and camera. Climbing mountains, reading philosophy and keeping fit with yoga.